DIEGO ALARCÓN

M.Sc. in Remote Sensing

@ diego.alarcondiaz@gmail.com Würzburg, Germany in diegoalarcondiaz

J 015255311223

diegoalarc

Leistenstraße 20. Würzburg 97082 DiegoAlarcnDaz2



ABOUT

Master in Remote Sensing and Land surveyor Engineer, with 9 years of experience in working with geographic information systems (GIS), extensive knowledge in software handling, human resource management and development projects. I work results-oriented and purposefully, try to make a valuable contribution to the organization and make decisions independently and critically.

EXPERIENCE

Customer Support Engineer UP42

Currently

Würzburg, GER

- Coordination and compliance review of restricted and commercial data access.
- Resolution of technical issues in console. API and SDK.
- Configuration and management of the Zendesk platform for Customer Support.
- Internal support to other teams in the use of GIS, python and other tools.

Senior GIS Analyst

Aguas Andinas

Nov 2018 - Sep 2019

Santiago, CL

- Support and update of the GIS Department database.
- Update of the geodesic network of the company by using geodetic GPS.
- Process optimization for internal company information using ArcGis and Python.

Survey Engineer

Digimapas Chile Aerofotogrametría Ltda

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Santiago, CL
- Survey of data in the field by means of Total Station and Geodetic GPS.
- Generation of digital cartography for various civil works and mining projects.
- Analysis of Lidar data for finished products in various civil works and mining projects.
- Processing of data obtained in the field.

Trainee Planning Engineer KTS Kabeltechnik GmbH

Apr 2018 - May 2018

Fulda, GER

• Fiber optic pipe and cabling planning for the regions of North Rhine-Westphalia and Hessen in the Federal Republic of Germany, with the use of GIS and aerial images.

Senior Project Engineer

Aconcagua Solutions

iii Oct 2016 - May 2017

Santiago, CL

- Data processing for filtering, increasing data quality and visualisation.
- Web scraping for public institutions information in Chilean and other South American companies.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Remote Sensing, **EAGLE**

Julius-Maximilians-Universität Würzburg

Sept 2019 - Dec 2021

B.S. in Surveying engineer Universidad de Santiago de Chile

Mar 2006 - Oct 2011

MOST PROUD

Innovation

Creation of the official R GeodesiCL package.

Education

Achieve the dream of doing an internship at the DLR in Germany.

Mentoring

Creation of the Geocodigos Chile project where I taught the principles of coding for the Geosciences.

MAIN SKILLS



LANGUAGES

Spanish **English** German



Field Analyst II

Here Maps

- **Sep 2013 Feb 2016**
- Santiago, CL
- Management of several projects, including Auto Dealership, Point of Interest, Extended lane.
- Field data collection using MultiCam technology.
- Data Base Engineer representative in Chile.

in sarah-schönbrodt-stitt-5b2556ba

sarah.schoenbrodt-stitt@uni-

Project Engineer

Municipality of Providencia

- **Apr** 2012 Feb 2013
- Santiago, CL
- Lead cartographic and IT implementation projects.
- Creation of an Excel Macro for the generation of Semiautomatic Report.

Msc. Jhonier Santa Maria Neira

@ Aguas Andinas

wuerzburg.de

REFERENCES

PhD. Sarah Schönbrodt-Stitt University of Würzburg

- in jhoniersantamaria

Project Engineer

Interra Chile

- **a** Jan 2012 Mar 2012
- Santiago, CL
- Manual classification of terrain data including generation of and editing of digital terrain models.
- Identification and interpretation of elements contained in orthoimages and subsequent generation of models.

Msc. Alejandro Barrionuevo

- @ Here Maps
- aabarrionuevo@gmail.com
- in alejandro-barrionuevo

Msc. Marius Witt

- PeTerra GmbH
- in marius-witt

EDUCATIONAL CORES

Master Thesis, EAGLE / Julius-Maximilians-Universität Würzburg

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Wüzrburg, GER

"Exploring the potential of remote sensing using machine learning to predict yields for table grape farms in Chile".

Applications:

- Data cleaning & preparation
- Python & R for Data Science
- The caret Package in R

- Remote sensing applications
- Machine learning applied to remote sensing

EAGLE Internship, German Aerospace Center (DLR)

Mar 2020 - Apr 2020

Oberpfaffenhofen, GER

Use of NTL-Sensors to analyse the use of EU funds for public investments.

Applications:

- Data preprocessing
- Calibration of NTL-Sensors

- Statistical aggregates & zonal histograms
- Time-series aggregation

Udemy & others

Continuous learning

Würzburg, GER

Learning different topics for Data Science.

Applications:

- Git+GitHub: A whole version control system from scratch
- 2022 Complete Python Bootcamp From Zero to Hero in Python
- Docker Essentials for Python Developers
- Machine Learning with R